does that Not freak you out have you
ever done that before that you can click
a button and accidentally cost yourself
like $500 not even $500 dude I read an
article on this that was like I
accidentally charged myself 14
Grand and I'm like oh no like this is
terrifying my God but um the response
from like the Google SME or whatever was
like dude I'm so sorry this happened to
you you know it was very emotionally
mature response too he is like you know
I can't imagine what it might must be
like to to you know see that number or
whatever but for you to do this you had
to be pretty
[Music]
[Applause]
dumb hey everyone we've all heard of
project Discovery right the authors of
nuclei htpx and countless other
essential security tools what you may
not have heard of however is their
conference hardly strictly security
conference this conference is happening
April 25th from 8: a.m. onward virtually
and it's featuring the topic of
everything open source security tooling
they'll have speakers from top companies
like versel dated dog hash Corp and
fastly and it's oriented towards anybody
who cares about open source security
tooling whether you're a Bug Hunter a
red teamer security leader whoever uh
there should be great content for you at
this conference so if you're interested
head over to nu. g/ hss2
24h ss24 right uh hardly strictly
security and then 2024 uh to sign up and
register and get in on that conference
goodness all right with that back to the
show dude I'm so freaking cold right now
like you got to turn your heat up no
it's not that man it's the cold showers
do you do the cold show hour no I don't
do I don't do that I I know a bunch of
you do that and I think you're crazy for
it dude like I don't normally do it very
often but like I was I've like I stopped
Lifting for a couple weeks and then I
getting back into it and I've been
pretty sore so I was like all right you
know let me see if I can do like a cold
shower and now I'm just like like core
cold you know like I'm not cold like I
I've got like plenty of clothes on and
like got even the heater is on the feet
right now but like something deep in my
core is just freezing freezing
interesting where where you at man
you're in a hotel today yeah yeah I'm up
in uh I'm in Upstate New York I'm in
Buffalo for the eclipse oh really oh you
went up there to see the eclipse huh
yeah yeah yeah I've got some friends up
here so I thought it would be a fun
little trip and uh yeah yeah it's it's
exciting it's a little cloudy right now
but I'm hoping that it clears up
hopefully so that that would suck if you
went there for that it was just straight
clouds for the whole Eclipse I saw this
crazy graph of like Airbnb bookings
right on that little band and like
everything is booked in that entire band
it's so interesting yeah um I mean the
hotels were like ridiculously expensive
really um because I've SP I've stayed
here in this area before and it's like
usually very you know normal hotel
prices and then it was like two or three
times minimum uh as much per night um
just dude that that sucks man that is
not a normal normal thing to pay rip
yeah it's it's a it's a little bit
ridiculous but I was able to find you
know a pretty good deal so all things
considered you got like the goggles or
whatever the glasses that you need I do
have the special glasses you know I've
got um you know these nice special
special glasses so you can look at the
Sun and stuff and they're basically like
paper welding goggles you know I I have
a vested interest in you being able to
see so uh please please protect your
eyes I would yeah I'm not going to stare
directly at the sun don't stare directly
at the Sun
great well what if you stare directly at
the
Moon okay
well got you on that one didn't see that
one coming did you oh my gosh dude okay
don't well maybe you can directly but I
don't know all right all right well
we'll leave that up to the experts in
you know astrology and we'll get back to
our our lane which is bug
Bounty where do we want to start out
today Joel We got a we got a decent
amount of things on the list today yeah
so there was this there was this really
cool um event that I saw um yes we hack
uh is running dude I saw that it's over
now I think they ran a live hacking
event um with Louis Vuitton which is
super cool um where was this event you
know I imagine it was I I believe it was
Paris um yes it was in Paris and I saw
you know I talked to a couple people
that went to the event and saw the
pictures online and it looked looks
pretty freaking well done you know yeah
it's pretty exciting I don't know if yes
Weck has run an event before have they
run live packing EV have done a couple
but I think this is the one that like
for me this is the one that put them on
the map with regards to like live
hacking events because it's like there
have been some small ones here there but
Louis Vuitton is a pretty cool Target
and you know it's in Paris and the the
pictures are really good the swag looked
really good looked like an awesome time
yeah I mean it looks really really sick
so I'm hoping to see more um more events
from the team but it's cool to see such
a large
like non-traditional brand doing an
event like that you know I'm sure uh
that other fashion brands and stuff are
going to see that and maybe hopefully
get interested in doing security events
would be super cool I know there's so
many um luxury brand lovers in the slag
for that for that like event just ah
imagine having like a custom Louis
Vuitton like freaking jacket that
they've got there I I don't even know so
I haven't even gotten confirmation I
imagine that this is the case but I
haven't gotten confirmation that those
are actually Louis Vuitton
jackets like I don't know but I don't
know the concept is still pretty cool I
if it if it was actually Louis Vuitton
jacket I would absolutely fly out just
for that you know for sure for sure yeah
I mean super cool right like once like
one time super epic Swag like that is
that's super cool it's such an enticing
uh enticing yeah so I'm not normally the
one to do stuff like that too I I
normally look at this like pretty from
like a business perspective like okay
you know I'm gonna have to spend
whatever however much on flying Mariah
out and like you know gonna go out to
the event that sort of thing this you
know the opportunity cost of hacking on
other programs when the bounties aren't
quite as high that of thing but like I
feel like there's a special niche of
Swag that's like pretty different which
something that holds mainstream sway
like Louis Vuitton right but I feel like
like if it was like all right we'll give
you like a I feel like I might do it for
like a custom laptop or like you know
something like that but also Louis
Vuitton jacket that would be that'd be
really rad so yeah yeah exactly I didn't
really put myself in the category of of
hackers that would go to a live hacking
event just for the swag not not
considering the bounties and that sort
of thing like like I probably wouldn't
spend a bunch of time on the program if
their bounties weren't great but I would
definitely go and hack for at least a
couple days for that yeah for sure I
mean absolutely you know hey if Louis
Vuitton wants to send uh send us invites
next time well for sure say I need to go
make a yes we hack account because I
don't even have a yes we hack account so
yeah that's true I don't think I have
one either that's probably not really
helping my chances yeah yeah I think we
got to you know do something here to get
to get on the board but uh no kid yeah I
was looking at the results I I dropped
that tweet in the in the doc Joel but
the results um for that live acument are
up and man dude team Spain they are just
crushing it with almost all of the um
all of the awards at this event went to
team
Spain yeah it looks like they they work
together the three of them cuz they all
have the same number of reports uh but
yeah they they really Crush in our boy
nagly of course you know right right not
not far behind them it's interesting
that they won first second third um
because like their points are different
even though they all have oh check that
out yeah by a couple number of reports
and stuff I'm not really sure maybe it's
just like the severity or I'm not really
sure how the reporting structure works
over there but um I would have expected
that they would have been like tied for
first so I think technically nag
actually got second uh if you're
ignoring the points but yeah yeah yeah I
I I don't know what do you think about
this what do you think about like a
points based leaderboard because I think
that was something that hacker one did
away with really quickly early on in the
live hacking event game as they were you
know kind of figuring that whole thing
out and I think pretty much every other
you know bug Bounty platform makes that
in my opinion mistake of doing it based
off of points in the beginning um rather
than doing it based off of money uh but
then we've seen the other we've seen bug
crowd and integrity both come around on
that and sort it by money now
um so I'm I'm kind of curious as to why
yes we hack isn't doing that yeah I
don't know um I'm not sure why they did
it but it's I mean it's an interesting
approach I think hacker one didn't like
the gamification aspect of it where um a
lot of people were just like finding
ways to gamify that to get on like the
top of the leaderboard where you know
money like Bounty amount is usually a
direct correlation with
impact so higher bounties higher impact
you know it's like a pretty good way of
sort of like measuring and like having
like a scoring mechanism but even on the
hacker one leaderboard you see that
there's other ways of sorting it too
yeah like they have sorting by like
number of reports and number of resolved
and like that kind of stuff too so it's
not all exclusively just money but I
think that money is a pretty good way of
measuring it maybe the points are their
their same uh sort of thing yeah yeah
maybe so I it definitely depends uh you
know I I mostly just pay attention to
the Bounty amount ones but then there's
also that aspect of like okay well when
you've got a tallying Bounty amount you
know total and
you have sorting by bounties and you
know they're those people that are like
nogly that write the scripts and are be
like all right Justin just got a you
know 15K Bounty all right note that down
in my little notebook like like like I
don't know why you know he does this but
he is like freaking Bounty uh uh you
know intelligence agency because you can
be like all right ngi how much did you
know Justin make at the PayPal event in
2023 and he'll give you like the number
within a 10% plus or minus somehow every
time I was like how do you know that
it's pretty crazy like he he really is
like tracking it somewhere somehow CU
it's um he definitely like has a lot of
data on that stuff like I remember one
time we were in our Discord and we were
chatting we were like he was like oh I
know how much everybody's made you know
like with their total Bounty amounts I
was like what's mine and he was like 10K
off I was like wow oh wow okay jeez ugly
man he's he's definitely got some some
data and you know that's that's one of
his things you know is data so uh it's
on brand but creepy nonetheless I must
say yeah a little bit a little bit the
nagly intelligence that workor you know
but yeah I I did um so shout out to team
Spain they did awesome shout out to Pik
Haka uh or Haka piku depending on where
you are in the uh you know if you're on
Discord or on um on Twitter uh they got
best dressed bug biggest impact that's
pretty awesome um and yeah looked like
an awesome event for sure um very very
cool yeah what's so what is this what is
this little this little note underneath
you have some Insider you have some
Insider information I do have some
Insider information so I I will you know
normally if it's ngly I'll throw nly
under the bus this one was not nogly but
I did talk to a couple other people um
from that event and one con that I can
say about that event is um the top
earners were not actually earning very
much the bounties were not awesome for
that event um so I can say
roughly assuming the the data is
accurate and I probably should double
check with ngi because he's got good
data on all this stuff too but it seems
like quite a bit off like it could be
somewhere between one5 to oneth of what
a a top earner at a any given live
hacking event is making or any given
hacker one live hacking event is making
so interesting that's a little bit do
you know why that was was it Bounty
table Bounty table I mean I I think it's
I mean it's got to be a combination of
bounty table and scope but I know that
there were some exclusive crits um that
were that were paid out you know one
person crits or whatever but I I believe
the the the Bounty table for that event
was not very high and that's why you
know it's a little bit a little bit
discrepancy between hacker one's live
hacking events and and something like
this super interesting yeah so that but
but I mean they're making like we said
they're making up for it with the with
the crazy you know Target and the crazy
swag because like how sick would it be
to be like I just was spent the weekend
hacking liby Vuitton like was pretty rad
I know right it's super cool that's
super cool I I love I mean that's always
like one of the really cool aspects of
the the LHS is like the name aspect and
like getting to hack these big companies
and stuff yeah all right dude let's
let's jump over to the browser market
share stuff because this is a really
interesting topic that we were having a
discussion around in the Discord
recently and so I went and like double
clicked on it a little bit and figured
out some details and I highlighted the
the interesting ones there in the doc
Joel but so I feel like a lot of people
throw around this this number of
like um Safari having a decent amount of
market share um in the browser space
because if you look it up it says like
18 like the second most used browser
yeah second most used browser
18.5% um and they still have not adopted
same site lacks default so uh that this
really affects you know
Ceres um but if you look into it a
little bit
more and you look at the breakdown for
this you know there's there's desktop
users and there's mobile users and maybe
I'm just thinking about this wrong but
um desktop users only have Safari only
has 8% of desktop users and they and
they have 24% of mobile users right
which which makes sense because iOS is
kind of a bigger platform on mobile for
sure um but I feel like a lot of the
apps that we hack are like not something
that you casually log into on your
phone you maybe I'm off with that
because I I know that the the statistics
are pretty high on like 70% of web
traffic is like mobile or something like
that but I feel like there you know when
reporting stuff to like this business
analytics platform or something like
that I feel like people aren't going to
be logging in on their phone and being
like all right let me run this report
and you know that sort of thing so I
feel like knowing what kind of Target
demographic your website that you're
hacking has and then being able to give
them browser specific exploits and
numbers on that could be a helpful thing
what do you what do you think about that
yeah that's a that's a good call out I
mean I think it is good to sort of break
it down into like the desktop and the
mobile because I that the total stats is
it always catches people off guard when
you tell them oh you know like uh why
don't you tell me like in order what are
the top three browsers and most people
are going to say oh like Chrome
Firefox um you know saari your Edge and
you're like nope Chrome Safari Edge like
what and you know yeah I mean Safari as
a whole almost has 20% of the market but
the reality is that it's mostly mobile
people um using iPhones because there's
so many iPhones and they don't use an
alternative browser they just use Safari
um that they have that large share
whereas Android you know the default
browser is Chrome and the browser most
people use on Android is Chrome which is
why they have such a high um Mobile
Share plus I mean I use iOS but I use
Chrome on my phone oh really as my
browser yeah yeah I think a lot of
people do um so it it is really
interesting and I think that's a good
like that's a good idea like you should
always kind of be framing your writeups
and your PC's and your bugs and stuff to
try and show the most imp for whatever
company you're hacking on so I think
also targeting sort of like you know
more people are like if this is a mobile
specific website then more people are
going to be likely to be using Safari
than they one on desktop and if there's
a safari specific vulnerability like
that you can take advantage of same site
lacks uh no default same site um you
know setting then yeah yeah no I think
that makes a lot of sense and 25% you
know that's a pretty decent chunk of
mobile traffic so if you are focusing on
a site like you said that has mobile
presence then that's very significant um
and not something that I was I was
super well acquainted with uh before um
but one thing that I I wanted to shout
out as well from looking at the
statistics was like Firefox if you look
at the total market share has only a
2.8% uh yeah you know presence and and
they're they're it's 0.5% in Mobile
right so nobody is using Firefox on I
don't know anybody who uses Firefox
mobile browser and I will say like I
think a lot of more people used Firefox
back in the day um it was a lot more
popular of a browser but then Chrome
like rocketed past it after a while
after after it sort of like gain
popularity and gain a lot of features
and stuff and then Firefox surged a
little bit when they did the the quantum
or whatever like the the rewrote their
Firefox like rewrote their engine to be
super fast and really optimized um and
that like gave it a Performance Edge on
Chrome and I think that surged their
popularity but now there's like so many
brows like you see Opera right like
Opera is now like I would say like a
marketing heavy browser where they're
like on social media a lot they sponsor
lots of like YouTube channels and stuff
2.5% almost yeah they have almost the
same market share as firef I would have
never thought that that was that was why
this was crazy to me was like Opera has
the same presence and more presence on
mobile than Firefox does but um Firefox
still has 6% of
desktop users which I thought was a
little bit higher than expected um so
there is there is you know it's still a
little bit hard to sell that because um
you know Firefox isn't doing same set
LAX either despite if you Google it it
says they are but they rolled it back
apparently I found out recently um uh
and it's so 6% of users like I I feel
like that might be a little bit of a
tricky sell if you're trying to talk
about it in a report but if you com
combine it with 8% from Safari and the
25% on mobile like there's a decent
amount of users that potentially could
get affected by a um same site or let me
see if I can say this properly a cross-
site attack right um a sea surf attack
uh without you know these these same
site lacks default Protections in place
so uh I don't know it's just helpful to
have the numbers and be aware of these
sort of things you know 15% on on
desktop 24% on mobile not insignificant
numbers um but I think this is also a
really good statistic for the people on
the program side as well because as much
as I hate to put you know SE severity
lowering weapons in your hands yeah
that's exactly what I was going to say
you know like the reality is that when
programs come back with these things you
know if anybody report something that's
like oh this only works on edge or this
only works on Firefox then
you know you can't really be surprised
when they're going to put a damper on
the severity or they're going to lower
your Bounty or whatever because if you
look at the raw numbers if it's not on
affecting
Chrome like well we'll start there if
it's not affecting Chrome then it's
already like in the minority missing
almost almost half of the market and
then if it's Notting yeah yeah right and
then if it's not affecting uh you know
Safari or Edge then that's the other
like third yeah I mean you're you're
basically at you know 10% or less of the
market so it's a very very difficult uh
case to make but you can still report it
nonetheless I I think programs will
still fix it it's just going to be way
lower impact yeah yeah I think so too
all right dude I'm going to tell you a
story from this week of uh of bug bounty
hunting because I was um let's see how
big do I want to make this I want to
make this pretty big I think I I was
signing up for a service that I will use
you know that I am using on a regular
basis um that has a bug bount program
that I'm aware of and that um let's say
within the past year and a half there
has been a a live hacking event on this
Target and
they're they got a lot of reports and a
lot of eyes it was a pretty big one you
know um and I found a bug uh well I was
signing up for this service that was
just like right in front of me you know
um so one it it and and I I looked back
in my logs and I looked at this endpoint
before and I missed it I missed this
exploit and what it was is this it was a
part of the O flow and it was just a
classic example of um being able to use
the at sign to bypass uh host
restrictions um on the redirect URI and
it they weren't allowing slash uh you
know in that username password section
on the on the left side of the app they
weren't allowing um uh backslash they
weren't allowing hashtag they weren't
allowing a bunch of stuff but they made
the mistake of allowing a question mark
in there which makes it a part of the
query um that you know and they were
still parsing it as if that part that
was following the AD Sign was the domain
rather than the part before um so that
allowed me to just completely hijack the
account and uh it would it had to be
sent to the root of my domain which is a
little tricky but uh I I had to go in
there and like edit my index.php page or
whatever um super interesting but yeah
being being making sure you know being
thorough with these sort of things when
you're testing these you know trying the
at sign trying the the the question mark
the hashtag the forward slash the back
slash all of the terminating characters
really important because sometimes you
get that one that just works so this was
in a username and it would allow you to
like do like basically like do like a
forgot password but it would
to totally different sorry so it an ooth
flow right with the redirect URI so you
know where it sends the code to you
afterwards and it's using the
username and password part you know for
basic o of the URL so you can do like
you know you can do like https uh col
test google.com and it'll still send it
to google.com but if you do test
question mark google.com then it'll send
it to
test right and so that was how I sort of
broke that off flow and they they still
said okay this host is you whatever host
it was but actually my my domain was
before the at sign terminated by a
question mark there and so the actual
browser navigated to my domain with the
valuable code that can be uh used as the
session token gotcha that's super cool
that's a cool bug man yeah you have to
tell me uh who who was on after I'll
tell you afterwards yeah it it's kind of
annoying that I missed it before but I
was I was like ah someone must have
found this and they just must have like
you think it was there the whole time oh
yeah it was there for sure I have
validation that it was there um W but uh
yeah it just somebody we we all missed
it and and it's like oh my gosh I can't
believe that happened um wow so yeah
kind of a crazy crazy one from this week
cool um I saw that you you made a tweet
about um kaido workflows yeah dude
finally okay so check this out
kaido is um dropping Global workflows
this week uh probably by the time this
airs but if not short shortly after um
and what this means is that you will be
able to build workflows and then reuse
them across different projects which is
something that I feel like should have
been there from the very beginning uh
but is something that the community has
been asking for for a little while and
it's really helpful because you can
build out these automations that make
your work your hacking workflows work I
mean that's why they're called workflows
much um much more efficient and uh so
I'm really looking forward to that
release plus they're easy to share now
too um thanks to even better um from
beex and I I wanted to shout out as well
that I in conjunction with the
announcement that this is going to be in
the next um you know release uh we saw a
bunch of PLL requests go into uh the K
kaido workflows repo on GitHub for a
bunch of really awesome um things like
generating A Cerf PC at like doing
something that should have been in birp
since forever which is um Json to form
form data and form data back to Json uh
yeah encoding for for the request body
um and these are all done by by yot um
cool and so definitely very high high
quality code and it's good to see
another another you know top haacker
investing into the kaido and
environment yeah this is really awesome
it's cool to see um it's cool to see
that there's like a community sort of
like you know way to contribute these
and share these with other people and
create a really awesome base of
different workflows um and like show
what's possible Etc yeah so yeah this is
really really cool previously you could
export them and stuff like that and then
reimport them into different projects
but it was kind of a pain so having
these be Global I think will be be
really helpful um um super awesome yeah
and we've been seeing a lot of more
investment into the kaido environment
lately which is cool um definitely
excited about that and excited about
building some stuff out I've got a I've
got a topic next week for the Pod that
I'm going to talk about some ideas for a
kaido plugin that I want to develop
slash maybe someone in the community
will develop who knows um uh that I'm
going to talk about so we'll we'll save
that one for next week though um that's
awesome dude so I was going back through
my uh bookmark tweets uh in prep for
this episode and I saw this tweet from
uh November
2023 uh and it was when we were talking
about like doing like aath app redirects
uh aath redirects to app schemes and
this this dude comments on it and and he
says uh at techn geek here instead of
malicious app installed uh a user could
directly steal the token if their server
uh to their server if the scheme
controlled is allowed
okay so it's a little bit a little bit I
I haven't read it out loud yet but uh
essentially what he's saying here is
that if if you can control any
scheme um for an app then you could just
trigger Google Chrome and then Google
Chrome has this uh Google Chrome
connate question mark URL equals that
will navigate Google Chrome to that
specific URL um
and so I don't know what do you think
about this do you think this is
something useful to use in a chain from
a mobile perspective or yeah so like I
said um I think Chrome is the default
browser on Android now so this does kind
of assume that Chrome is installed um
but it probably is I think in most cases
it's not to say you know people haven't
downloaded Firefox or some other opera
or whatever on their phone but think
probably in most cases I I'd really like
to see the breakdown actually by OS for
um mobile for what the browsers um are
because I'd imagine like Android is
probably very very high percent oh yeah
using Chrome that being said um there
are definitely some good cases to use
this so if you were to just open htb or
https by default the system is going to
use your browser or it's going to prompt
you to use any app that can open browser
links so it does almost the same thing
but I think if there's some sort of
check for example like say um say the
app is checking where where a link you
know any link that gets opened what's
the what's the scheme
um and if it's checking for HTP and htps
and doing some extra logic there you
could bypass that with Google Chrome um
you know if you instead just link out
directly to the Google Chrome app and
then have that open the URL for you you
don't have to worry about the app logic
trying to you know prevent you from
going to a certain URL or parsing the
host or something like that if it's
looking at the HTTP
schemes um but yeah I think this is a
this is a really creative way of you
know sort of in implicit it's not really
open reader it's it's like an implicit
open reader it's a gadget you know I
mean it's it's a gadet good gadget for
mobile stuff for sure um yeah I I hadn't
really of course you know you could just
use the HTTP htps scheme that that makes
sense too if any scheme is being
permitted um but yeah like you said if
there was restrictions around those then
that that could be interesting I I wish
there was some way in Mobile for you to
do something like what we just talked
about for the other aat thing where it's
like you know I could do whatever at
Google
Chrome naate question mark URL equals
blah blah blah you know that would be
really cool if there was some way to
like essentially trash some text uh so
there are some ways um one of the ways
not prefix text right not pre Yeah so
basically it would have to start with
the same scheme like it would have to be
like Google Chrome call SL SL and then
the parsing problem yeah um but there
are some ways to do it I believe baggy
Pro's gold URL tricks
um we talk about this all the time yeah
we talk about this one all the time but
I'm fairly certain there's some tricks
in there that still work um for this
type of you know host like parsing
problems with like backslashes and ATS
and
stuff yeah that we we'll have to I have
to double double check that I feel like
I can't read this um you know right up
by
Pro enough times like every time I come
back to this like the gift that keeps on
giving or something like that um but
yeah I think that could also be another
really interesting area of research is
like let's look into the Android scheme
parsing uh I me we have the source code
so we can just look at the source code
um and see how that works specifically
if there's any way for us
to in you know put some text in there
get it parsed as a different part of the
scheme or something like that that would
allow us to do something with starts
with because I feel like a lot of these
redirects for mobile are like okay
starts with Google Crome
you know if that was what it was
redirecting to or starts with you know
snap or whatever um and then if it does
then they're like all right whatever um
so if you could find a way to redirect
to a different scheme uh like the Google
Chrome scheme then you could xal trade
out pretty much anything you want um via
those ooth flows which would break a ton
of websites yeah no kidding yeah yeah
absolutely um I saw this really cool
thing on Twitter while we're talking
about Twitter I think a lot of this
stuff today is from Twitter but um you
mentioned that there was this guy who's
been doing a really
awesome self documentation self blog
type of thing yeah um of your Bug Battle
you method this is the methodology that
you tweeted a long time ago right yeah
sort of so I I won't take full credit
for this um as far as like oh you know
this guy and I'm I'm sorry dude I'm
gonna butcher your name but it's Shas
shus shus
shvan um and essentially what they did
is they they did one of these really
cool detailed writeups that we talk
about from time to time on the Pod um
but essentially he's saying the the road
map I I followed to make 15K in Bounties
in my first eight months starting from
zero and if you look at the the notion
site that he links out to very detailed
you know he's got exactly how many hours
he spent each month how many days he
worked how much Bounty he's got how many
reports he submitted number of programs
Etc um and uh just very very detailed
stuff and you know I won't say that this
is
like the best pathway that someone could
have taken you know in my opinion if you
read through his actual road map I think
there's a lot of things in there or
there's a couple things in there that
that um I wouldn't necessarily agree
with but one of the things that he does
uh mention and he doesn't give me credit
for this specifically so I'm not trying
to steal credit for this just just to be
clear um although he does shout us out
at the in one of the tweets at the
bottom of the of the red up um is this
whole concept of making sure you're
doing enough hacking while you're
learning so he talks about this concept
of 60% hunting 40% learning 80% you know
hunting 20% learning you know making
that shift as you're continuing to grow
and this is something that I'm telling
people in the ctbb Discord all the time
that are that are new that message me
and are like hey what do I do you hack
you you get out there and you fail and
you fail and you fail and you fail and
you look at that as a part of your
training because it is and eventually
you can only bang your head into a wall
for so long and uh before the wall
breaks down yeah so yeah I mean being
failure vers is like good but you also
have to learn when it's productive right
like to fail and so you know getting
that hands-on experience is really
important what do what do you mean by
that what do you mean by by being
failure averse is is good well I think
like there are lots of areas in life
where being failure verse is even life
or death right like for example like
driving a car right like if you take the
wrong turn or you turn at the wrong time
like that could be potentially fatal um
but
that's not but like in bug Bounty if you
take the wrong turn it's not f
right like that's a learning experience
um and that's something that can be
useful but it can also be a really big
time sync so training yourself to be
able to identify those situations and
spend time failing so that you can
better identify when something is not
necessarily a failure or when you can
trust your gut or not trust your gut
like we talked about last week um you
know there's a lot of aspects of bug
bounding where failing can be good or
can lead you to find other things that
you know maybe gadgets or things that
are just like you know useful to know um
but it's important to push yourself to
go into those areas even if it might not
feel comfortable even if you think that
you are going to fail just because there
might be more there than you realize
yeah I I I thought I disagreed with you
on that but I think I do agree you know
there's there's there are areas where
it's do or Doom you know um but I think
bug Bounty is an area where and I think
most most skills that you're trying to
learn rather than actions you're trying
to perform like driving a car or
something like that
um should be failure should be looked at
as almost a celebration of having done
the thing in the first place you know um
and and as a part of the process 100% uh
and so I think that for people like me
who are essentially success obsessed I I
am very driven by success and uh the the
feeling of achievement
um right I think it's really hard to
reframe that but if you can then it'll
help you push through those beginner
stages which I think is what deters
almost everyone uh yeah because those
beginner stages can be really difficult
when you're failing and failing and
failing and failing yeah for sure and
I'm the same way you know I I I don't
think anybody really likes to fail yeah
um but you can learn to you know sort of
fail elegantly or you know take it not
as a failure but as a learning process
yeah for sure a couple a couple more
things I wanted to to shout out on on
this write up one I just appreciate the
commitment to it you know how much
detail went into recording all this
stuff and then putting it on a public
you know page where people can benefit
from seeing your consistency and um to
achieve your goals and I also want to
highlight that um around nine months in
he started in July he um uh did this in
wrote this up in March um he started to
actually see some good traction last
month he made 14 Grand excuse me uh 14
Grand from from bug Bounty um and this
is very it's not consistent with that
write up that I that I did um on my
that's pinned to my Twitter profile um
in that he should have been seeing sort
of increasing amounts of bounties as he
continues to go um over the past couple
months but um he is seeing his first
five figure month about n months in you
know8 to n months in which I think is
about accurate I think you could get to
the point where you're making uh you
know five figures a month in bug bounty
after really really working your ass off
for for nine months yeah which is a
really good reality check too I think a
lot of people don't really they think
like okay like I'm going to you know
read some stuff for a month and then I
get bounties next month right it's like
no not really yeah yeah there's
definitely going to be you know small
bounties and failures along the way um
but seeing these sort of writeups are
with transparent details really really
encouraging especially when it's been
such a long process for this I mean this
is 600 hours put into this thing so um
definitely applaud this person's
commitment and uh yeah man if I could
long a person you know if I could invest
into a person uh I would be willing to
bet that this person's going to make a
chunk in bugb in the future um that's
awesome that's that's High Praise from
from you that's awesome yeah man I I can
see the writing on the wall for sure um
and another another piece of that was
that he said hey I'd you know as step
nine of his process I'd recommend
reading at least a thousand of the
hacker one reports yeah I don't even
know how many hacker one reports are
there you know I don't even know but he
he said that he went through and read a
bunch of them um and I think that takes
a lot of commitment to go through and
read a lot of those um I will say
disclosed hacker one reports are like
free blog posts yeah it's it's a really
good resource for just understanding how
other hackers think and what stuff leads
to um vulnerabilities and like why it's
impactful and especially when there's
like good good communication between the
program and the researcher and stuff
like it's really it's nice to see those
kinds of examples that you can think
about in your own Communications and on
your own reports yeah 100% And and sort
of I in line with that I I kind of also
want to recommend one other blog uh mon
hacks um this is by Kieran um and he's
every I read these every single week or
every single time he sends them out uh
sort of an update on his uh his 100 hour
Bounty challenge he's at 13 and a half k
um and he's got 63 hours left so he's
only you know 37 hours in so he's doing
pretty well um but this is another
person that's kind of doing a an update
on a pretty regular basis we mentioned
Alex Chapman doing an update on a pretty
regular basis of their Bounty progress
so I really like this trend think it's I
think it's encouraging for the
community yeah sweet yeah I totally
agree um all right let's see what else
we got on the on the um on the list for
today um okay so I'm gonna I'm gonna
jump to the last one real quick and then
we'll come back um sure so once again
going through the bookmarks on uh on
Twitter super valuable uh and I noticed
this uh checked one today by the way
yeah yeah it's helpful man you know it's
hard to go back through and and like
look at those on a fairly regular basis
uh just because you forget but when you
for me you know when I'm in an
environment where I'm like oh let me try
to you know deliver the most high
quality bug VY content I can I that's a
place for me to get data um so it's nice
I really like that about prepping for
these podcasts that I get to go back and
sort of review that stuff um yeah for
sure and one of the Nuggets that I found
was a post from Port sger research just
just probably about a month ago yeah a
month ago um announcing that they had a
highquality contribution to their xss uh
cheat sheet by someone named H machine
or Hans machine um and this is the use
of the on form data um sort of event
handler and the the payload is is form
tag on form data equals alert one and
then inside the form tag there's a
button and if you click it it Triggers
on form data
um not not something really super
revolutionary but cool nonetheless might
definitely get you past some some laughs
um but more so Joel I kind of wanted to
talk about the process for this because
it's
like how do new event handlers get added
you know into into chromium or like why
are we just figuring out about this now
um so I went down this tangent of
like let me see how this happens and
here well for Joel do you know where it
happens just just to test your I do now
but I I didn't I didn't before okay well
one of the yeah thank you for actually
reading my document then
um um uh essentially what I discovered
was one of the best places to see where
this is happening is the
blink uh blink Dev Google group and
blink which blink is the like the code
word for Chrome right is that am I
correct you know I think it is the code
word for Chrome's HTML maybe not just
HTML just its
renderer um okay which is I'm not really
sure yeah yeah here we go blink is the
rendering engine used by chromium yeah I
think it's chromium's rendering engine
and they do this awesome thing in this
Google group where they
will uh put like a a post up and you
know get comments from the community on
um on any feature that they intend to
ship so they'll prefix the the subject
of the message to the Google group with
intent to ship blah blah blah and I'm
just like cool perfect you know like
like that is exactly what I want to see
um so for the for the critical thinkers
in the um in the ctbb Discord I went
ahead and added a uh a channel exclusive
channel that will um give us an alert
anytime there's a new uh update to this
this feed uh and so we can stay on top
of what things blink is intending to
ship and stay on top of what features we
may be able to exploit uh
in that those new functionalities yeah
it's super awesome I mean this is one of
those really um unique things that we
are trying to provide to the critical
thinkers as you know extra value for um
subscribing and being part of that
community and um you know so if you want
to be on the front edge of all those new
features that are being added into
Google and the rendering engine and new
event handlers and all that kind of
stuff and get the excess before anybody
else does um you know definitely go
ahead over to the ctbb Discord um
discord.gg CBB right yeah we've got that
one or we've got ctbb doow Discord that
one works too so either those links they
should take you right to the server and
um yeah we have a new channel there
intent to ship and it's monitoring for
those uh those changes which is super
awesome it wasn't it wasn't like
something super hard to implement and
obviously you can just like subscribe to
the you know Google group if you want
but they're going to like bomb you with
emails because it's a very active Google
group um so maybe could set something up
where it's like some fancy filter or
something like that that's I don't even
know how you would do that but uh I've
got it all coded up and and pushed into
the Discord bot now um so quick quick
win for any of you that are critical
thinkers or past guest speakers that
have access to that channel um I'm I'm
definitely going to keep keep an eye on
it dude there's some really cool ones in
here um I didn't actually put this in
the in the doc sorry about that but I
I'll I'll put it in Discord right now
here go to that go to that link um
one of the ones that was kind of
interesting was these Rex modifiers that
they're intending to ship that they
announced um late March that they were
intending to ship um where as a part of
the Rex it looks like you can add uh a
flag for various things like um you know
the I the M the S Flags inside the
actual pattern making something like uh
case insensitive and and that sort of
thing which I feel like is pretty useful
for regular expression
injection you see that super interesting
yeah and what's what's even more
interesting is it seems like there's
people who are on
this on this like mailing list or
whatever or who are like reviewing this
stuff who work at other companies yeah
yeah there is there's like some Shopify
people and that sort of thing yeah yeah
yeah so I super I don't know they've got
this like looks good to me one looks
good to me two looks good to me three
you know yeah I I I wonder what because
the group is open to anyone so I could
just respond and be like looks good to
me like some random dude you know like
XC XC round two yeah like looks great um
so yeah but definitely a cool place to
to look around and read through I know
there's some some um CSS uh stuff that's
being pushed soon regarding
transitions um there's
some I don't even some of this stuff is
like way like I like like this one
declarative Shadow Dom serialization
like what's a shadow Dom like that
sounds like super that's the secret Dom
that runs all the other Dom yeah well
either that or something else but um uh
yeah it's there's there's definitely
some some deep browser knowledge that
could be gained from reading through
these and kind of understanding how this
whole process flows so I thought it'd be
a cool shout out this is always
something that's fascinated me um you
know how how this stuff is like where
it's defined and how it's defined and
and so yeah this is super cool um I'm
definitely going to be doing some deep
dives into a bunch of these different
issues and poll requests and stuff and
just figuring out how this stuff works
yeah all righty man um last last topic
that I had today uh for today was I was
just going to give you sort of like a
rundown of the CDN CGI research that I
was talking about from before that I
said that I would do and I have somewhat
done in a a rare turn of events okay the
turn I mean this is execution incredible
so all right you know what before we get
into that actually let's talk about that
because um I don't like that I just said
just flicked that that cup over there I
don't like that I just said that in a
rare turn of events I have followed
through on the research that I would
like to be doing um but I feel like it's
hard as a book bunny Hunter and as a
full-time book Bounty Hunter to
justify spending a bunch of time
researching for zero days or you
something like that on a specific Target
when you do not have an application for
that do do you feel that I mean yeah I
mean and we talked about this because
one of the things that we wanted to look
at is kind of like this um like one of
the things we wanted to look at was a a
piece of software yeah that I mean there
are everybody a lot of people use it so
I'm sure we'll be able to find instances
of it but that being said it is a huge
time investment and um energy invest
into something that may or may not pan
out it doesn't have like a immediate um
impact at the moment and it's also like
longer scale research but I think it's
still worth it you know like I think um
depending on what it is and depending on
how much time you spend on it it can be
really worth it and it can be one of
those things that depending on how
widely it's used you know I think we
talked about this right like imagine you
find an xss Z day in Google ads or
Google tag manag or Google analytics
right like any of those things that are
used on such a large percentage of the
internet right like you can imagine the
the impacts of that would be very very
Broad and sweeping so that's probably a
place to spend you know where your time
investment is going to be worth it but
if it's some really abstract tool that
it's only used by one company you should
probably be looking at that one
company's Bounty table and deciding if a
zero day in this piece of software is
going to pay off and be worth it yeah
yeah and and I mean like a zero day in
in Cloud
flare I mean when again it would have
large reaching impact but it is a one
place fix as well like and sort of the
motivation for because we talked about
at the beginning of this year you know
wanting to do some more research this
year so I was kind of reviewing that
goal and being like all right you know
maybe I should lean a little bit more
research heavy for the next couple
months and
um yeah
like the things that have one location
fix are probably not that great for us
as BG bounty hunters like if I pop
something on CDN CGI I'm going to feel
super cool and it's going to be super
badass uh but then I'm going to you know
even if I report it to like
everyone then then it's going to be like
okay you know Cloud Player needs to fix
it because you can't even really put a
laugh in front of a laugh you know like
um and so then Cloud play is gonna fix
it it's gonna fix it for everyone and I
probably would just get the one Bounty
from from cloud flare you know because
everyone else doesn't really have an
actionable remediation step um right and
and so I don't know you maybe there's
there's cool research there maybe
there's maybe there's not but um I'll
talk about the methodology nonetheless
so I I wanted to see you know what are
all the files that
are available via this uh CDN CGI
endpoint and so I did I did something
scary and I went to to Google big query
and I queried the HTTP archive data set
man and hopefully you used the prepaid
card dude okay so does that Not freak
you out have you ever done that before
that you can click a button and
accidentally cost yourself like $500 not
even $500 dude I read an article on this
that was like I accidentally charged
myself 14
Grand and I'm like oh no like this is
terrifying my God but um the response
from like the Google SME or whatever was
like dude I'm so sorry this happened to
you you know it was very emotionally
mature response too he was like you know
know I can't imagine what it might must
be like to to you know see that number
or whatever but for you to do this you
had to be pretty dumb essentially was
and he's like for example this is the
query that would cost
$114,000 and essentially he's like
select Star on Star you know it's like
it's like like why would you run that
and and uh and so I don't know it was a
good cautionary tale for me but I was
like sweating as I pressed the Run
button
and like trying to figure out exactly
like how to optimize all this but at the
end of the day I queried the whole HTP
archive for every um CDN
CGI uh URL that I could find and I've
been kind of piecing through them
there's some really interesting looking
JS files there um that are kind of small
so pretty able to be parsed and stuff
like that um and I might drop the that
whole list of of um files into the the
ctbb disc when I'm once I'm done with
the research just if anybody else wants
to do some follow-up research um cool
but one of the ones that was most
interesting uh was this whole um Sur
concept surrounding the the email hiding
feature of of cloud flare and I went and
I found a tweet by um masot kinugawa
which I think we mentioned before on the
Pod um about a a xss auditor bypass so
you remember when Chrome had like yeah
xss audit aitor um they were able to use
this sort of chain to bypass xss auditor
and run arbitrary you know uh JS code
but but it still works so if if you look
at this if you we'll link the the tweet
in the description um in masato's
website is
down but um the the the payload is this
SVG and then he does a script tag and
then he does uh SVG and then the data-
CFE email and then a encoded string um
attribute okay and then a bunch of other
stuff and then what ends up happening is
the code for the email or hiding thing
will go through and decode hex decode
whatever is in that data CF email um
attribute it's just CF email oh yeah CF
email I mean that makes sense Cloud
Player email um yeah it'll decode
whatever's in there and then just
replace that whole tag with it
uh and and I was like and it uses in
HTML and everything man and I was like I
was poking at it for so long trying to
be like there's got to be like some way
for me to escape this but not that I can
find um okay and and so I don't think
there's any like xss or anything there
but it is a very cool way for you to use
cloudflare to obus gate your payloads
and also um sort of like we learned from
the the um masatu
kinugawa team's research SE sometimes um
various HTML parsers and stuff like that
will allow you to specify I think
actually Dom purifies default allows you
to specify data Dash attributes um and
and so that could allow you to smuggle
some payloads through because there's
some postprocessing that's being done
with it uh via This Cloud flare uh
script man there's there's a lot of
really interesting things with like
those data attributes um there's some
other Frameworks that use that type of
stuff like
um angular is it angular NG like NG data
and NG yeah all that kind of stuff like
super super weird funky behavior and I
bet there's probably more of this stuff
you said that you've done some research
so I imagine that there's there there is
some additional stuff I just mostly that
one that kind of blew my mind uh from
that teams research that I mentioned a
second ago of of NG and it being able to
be specified as a class attributes so
inside the HTML tag class equals ng-
iton JavaScript and that will just get
run was like what um you know what's
funny dude is I I I like somebody had
some relevant um you know CP about that
on Twitter and I was like I I posted a
picture of that screenshot and it
ratioed hard you know and it was like
blowing up like oh wow this is this is
really interesting I'm like yeah we
talked about it on the Pod and Mas to
released it months ago you know so I
don't know man it's good but it's good
to get the Distribution on
that yeah it's super super cool well
this is awesome yeah I'm looking forward
to uh to seeing that list um yeah yeah
so I'm gonna I'm gonna continue doing a
little bit of research on it um the the
JS files are really interesting
unfortunately there hasn't been much
that's panned out it's actually a little
bit less scope than I thought it was
it's just a lot of the same files so I'm
condensing it down a little bit trying
to find the outliers um but I would say
probably optimistically I'm looking at
like a CSP bypass rather than a an you
know a global Cloud flare xss just kind
of looking at the the writing on the
wall there so yeah we'll see how that
goes yeah
absolutely um all right man I think
that's it is that a wrap I think that's
a wrap all right sweet peace that's SP
see you and that's a wrap on this
episode of critical thinking thanks so
much for listening and if you want more
critic thinking content head over to
ctbb show/ Discord join the Discord
there's lots of great conversations and
chats going on over there and if you
want to support the show there's the
Discord subscriber tiers which give you
access to master classes amas hack
alongs exclusive scripts and an
exclusive chat Channel with us we'll see
you
[Music]
there